仙
境
奇
缘
第一季  第八集
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：冰蓝  欧沈娜  阿噻  如是我闻  潇湘月影  米苏
■
校对：米苏   时间轴：冰蓝  木讷  雨之
后期：灰灰是菇凉   总监：wdjmhs
■
《仙境奇缘》前情提要
Previously in Wonderland...
容我向你们介绍  你们的皇后
I give you your queen!
我的所有之物  都是我自己争取来的
Everything I have, I had to take.
那么你的所失之物呢
What about everything you've lost?
安娜斯塔西娅
Anastasia!
你
You?
别再小看我了  贾法尔
Stop underestimating me, Jafar.
瓶子在我的手上
I have the bottle.
找到他  精灵逃跑了
Find him! The genie escaped.
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.
我们本是朋友
We were friends.
他怎么能那样背叛我呢
How could he just betray me like that?
女王陛下  我已经履行了我的义务
Your majesty, I-I've fulfilled my obligation--
-我...  -承诺就是用来违背的
- I, uh... - Promises were made to be broken.
我许的愿望好像是流星
I believe I was promised falling stars,
但只有星星
and yet... just stars.
耐心点  就快了
Be patient. It's almost time.
太不可思议了
That's incredible.
据说
You know, they say,
在流星下接吻
one kiss under the falling stars,
会给你带来好运
and it brings you good fortune.
如果你想吻我
If you want to kiss me,
没必要编个故事出来啊
you don't have to make up a story.
这是真的
It wasn't a story.
这是什么
What's this?
是个小玩意儿  没什么
Ah, it's a trinket. It's nothing.
这挺漂亮的啊
It's a very nice nothing.
是别的姑娘送你的吗
Was it from another girl?
算是吧
In a way.
是我妈妈送我的
It's--my mother gave it to me.
你妈妈
Your mother?
我还不知道精灵也有妈妈呢
I didn't know genies had mothers.
她也是精灵吗
Was she a genie as well?
不  她是人类
No, she was quite human.
就和我出生时一样
As was I when I was born.
你是说
You mean...
你并非生下来就是精灵
you haven't always been a genie?
你怎么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
因为我现在是精灵
Oh, because I'm a genie now,
恐怕我以后会一直当精灵了
and I fear I shall be a genie for the rest of my days.
我当人类的日子已经很遥远了
My life as a human was a long time ago.
你妈妈呢  她还...
And your mother? Is she still--
我不知道
I don't know.
这个罗盘
This compass...
拥有强大的魔法
it has great magic.
一直向我指引着她的方向
And it always pointed me towards her.
我在瓶子里关着的那些年里
It was the only thing I kept with me
我就带着这个罗盘
in the bottle for all those years I was a prisoner.
它能给我慰藉
It provided me comfort.
我知道她在外面
I knew she was out there.
几年前  它...
And then some years ago, it...
不再指示方向了
just stopped pointing.
对不起
I'm sorry.
站起来
Stand up.
离那姑娘远点
And step away from the girl.
我们花了很长时间
It took us a long time, boys,
但终于找到一个精灵了
but we finally found ourselves a genie.
看来愿望真的会实现
Looks like wishes do come true.
你想要什么都行  但求求你放了她
I will give you whatever you desire, but please let her be.
我要她干什么
What would I want with her?
一旦我的愿望实现
Once I get my wishes,
就能得到一百个像她那样的姑娘
I could have a hundred like her!
现在
Now...
你的瓶子在哪  精灵
where is your bottle, genie?
离这里很远  但我可以带你过去
It's far from here, but I can take you to it.
你最好说的是实话
Better be telling the truth now.
我可是不好惹的
I am not to be trifled with!
幸运的是
Fortunately...
她也不好惹
neither is she.
看来星星真的给我们带来了好运
I guess the stars did bring us luck.
他们都没划伤我
They barely even scratched me.
爱丽丝
Alice...
爱丽丝  不要
Alice, no!
杰克  你吓我一跳  去哪儿了
Knave. You gave me a fright. Where were you?
抱歉  大自然在召唤我
Sorry, nature was calling.
真的吗  它说了什么
Really? What did it say?
相信我  你不会想听到的
Nothing you want to hear, trust me.
那些守卫是在找我们吗
So those guards out there-- they're looking for us?
不  他们在找一个逃跑的人
No. They're looking for someone who's escaped.
他们在找塞勒斯
They're looking for Cyrus.
那就好
Oh, well, that's good then.
那怎么算好消息
How is that good news?
因为他们还在找他
'Cause if they're still looking for him,
就说明他们还没找到他
it means they haven't found him yet.
但这只不过是时间问题
But it's only a matter of time,
所以我建议我们也开始寻找
so I suggest we start looking, too.
其实我们没那必要
Actually, we don't have to.
为什么
Why is that?
因为我知道他要去哪
Because I know where he's going.
那会是哪里呢
Where might that be?
他知道的唯一安全的地方
The only place he knows where he'll be safe.
在仙境里吗
In Wonderland?
贾法尔和红心王后还在找他呢
With Jafar and the Red Queen after him?
我觉得这种地方不存在
I doubt such a place exists.
有的
There is.
他只是得在他们找到他之前  赶去那里
He just needs to get there before they get him.
这是什么
What's this?
拜托
Come on!
Come on...
拜托  帮帮忙
Come on, a little help.
总有办法脱身的
There's got to be a way out of this.
拜托
Come on!
精灵
The genie.
谢谢你  葡萄藤
Thank you, grapevine.
我相信王后会很高兴的
I believe the queen will be quite pleased.
如您要求  大人
As you requested, sire.
你取走它时没人发现你吧
You were able to procure it with no incident?
是的
Yes.
女王完全不知情
The queen has no idea.
你...你会保护我不受她伤害吗
Uh, you--you'll protect me from her?
不久之后她就不再重要了
Soon she will no longer matter.
感谢你的牺牲
Thank you for your sacrifice.
-女王陛下  -干嘛
- Your majesty. - Hmm...
我从葡萄藤那听到了点消息
I've heard something through the grapevine.
说吧
Yes?
那个精灵在森林里被抓住了
Th-the genie has been captured in the forest.
他现在是你的了
He's yours now.
干得漂亮
Spectacular!
我们去把他带回来吧
Let's go retrieve him, shall we?
你好像没在分享我的喜悦啊
Well, I'm sensing you're not sharing my enthusiasm.
-你怎么了  -是我哥哥的事
- What is it? - It's my brother.
亲爱的  我对你们的手足相残不感兴趣
Darling, your sibling rivalry does not interest me.
我担心他做了件坏事
I fear he may have done a bad thing.
考虑到你们俩的智商
Considering both of your mental limitations,
我觉得应该没什么需要我担心的事
I'm not sure it's something I need to worry about.
我看见他给了贾法尔一个东西
I saw him give something to Jafar.
什么
What?
一个包裹  偷偷给他的
A bag. Handed it to him in secret.
包裹里面有什么
What was in it?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是我马上就来找您了
But I came to you right away.
我不知道里面有什么  我很抱歉
I don't know what it is, and I'm sorry.
不用道歉
No need for apologies.
趁我还没想杀掉报信人之前快走
Now leave before I decide to kill the messenger.
所以我们要去哪
So where are we headed?
你所谓安全的地方到底在哪
Where exactly is this safe place of yours?
在边境
The outlands.
所以我们要一路走到边境去吗
We're gonna walk all the way to the bloody outlands?
你就不能找个近点的地方吗  比如...
You couldn't have picked someplace closer, like...
其它任何地方
Anywhere else?
我和塞勒斯还在一起的时候
Back when Cyrus and I were together,
我们说好  如果有天我们走散了
we made a deal that if we ever got separated
或者发生了什么事  我们会在那里重聚
or if anything ever happened, we'd always meet back there.
你有在那留点吃的吗
Any chance you've left any food there?
我可以吃一点...
I could use a bit of--
在去那之前  我得先去个地方稍作停留
I just need to make a stop before we arrive.
那是当然了  我们去哪
Oh, of course we bloody do. Where now?
白兔的家
The white rabbit's house.
别这样
Oh, come on.
我知道你很记恨它背叛了我们
I know you're ticked off about how he betrayed us,
但现在真是找它算账的好时机吗
but is this really the time to settle a score?
我不是想报仇  杰克  我需要帮助
I don't want revenge, Knave. I want help.
让它帮忙吗  它可是个叛徒啊
From him? He's a bloody traitor.
它也是我们唯一逃出仙境的办法
And he's our only way out of Wonderland.
你还不懂吗
Don't you see?
只要贾法尔和红皇后还活着
With Jafar and the red queen alive,
我们在这永远都不安全
we'll never be safe here.
你  我和塞勒斯今天必须离开
You, me, and Cyrus, we need to leave today.
而只有兔子能带我们逃走
And the rabbit's the only one that can take us away.
在它做出这些事之后  我们不能相信它
We can't trust him, not after what he's done.
它和我以前是朋友  很好的朋友
He and I were friends once. Good friends.
这真的不合情理
It just doesn't make sense.
也许它只是得到了更好的条件
Maybe he just got a better offer.
有时候人们会背叛你
Sometimes people turn on you,
而你永远也不明白为什么
and you'll never understand why.
不对  它这么绝情地背叛了我们
No. For him to betray us that bad,
肯定有它的理由
there has to be a reason.
开门  求你了兔子  快开门
Open up! Please, rabbit, open the door!
来了  来了  小声点
All right, all right. Keep it down.
你想要吵醒所有...
Do you want to wake the whole famil--
爱丽丝  怎么了
Alice! What happened?
我们受到了攻击  我们需要帮助
We were attacked. We need help.
只有她能提供的帮助
The kind of help only she can provide.
好了
All right now.
你们俩  别挡我的路  快走
Ugh! You two, get out of my way! Shoo!
让一下  去站在我的药前面
Excuse me. Standing in front of my willow root.
她会好起来吧
Is she going to be all right?
药糊会让她好起来
This poultice will help her along.
你的唠叨却没什么用
Your fretting, not so much.
我不能什么也不做
Well, I can't just do nothing.
小声点
Shh!
孩子们还在睡觉呢
The children.
对不起
I'm sorry.
原谅我  我就这么闯进你的家
Forgive me. I've barged into your home, and--
你做得对
And a good thing you did,
要不然她活不过今晚
or she wouldn't survive the night.
但现在最好帮助她的方法
But the best way to help her now
就是让我做我的事
is to let me do my work.
你是来收工的吗
You've come to finish the job?
不全是
Not exactly.
我们去兜兜风怎么样
Shall we go for a ride?
那取决于我们要去哪了
Well, that depends where we're going.
你应该待的地方  亲爱的
Where you belong, darling.
回你的瓶子里去
Back to your bottle.
终于到手了
At last.
不
No!
地方不错啊
Nice spot.
一只兔子都住得比你好的时候
There's something wrong in the world
这世界肯定是出了问题
when a rabbit has a nicer flat than you do.
这地方看起来不一样了
It looks different here.
这些草都没人打理
The grass is overgrown.
萝卜也发霉了
The carrots are all moldy.
也许它已经不住这里了
Maybe he abandoned the place.
或者它只是希望别人这么以为
Or maybe that's just what he wants people to think he did.
兔子  是我  爱丽丝
Rabbit, it's me. It's Alice.
兔子
Rabbit!
我们还能在其他什么地方找到它吗
Any other idea where we might find him?
可以
Yes.
在这里面能
In here.
兔子
Rabbit?
你在哪  我知道你在里面
Where are you? I know you're in here.
我在这里  爱丽丝
Over here, Alice.
我任你处置
Do what you want with me.
其他人已经处置过我了
Everyone else has.
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
我
I...
我背叛了你  爱丽丝  背叛了你和塞勒斯
I betrayed you, Alice. You and Cyrus.
还有我
And me.
是的  还有你  杰克
Yes, even you, Knave.
兔子
Rabbit...
我们已经知道了
we already know.
而且知道已久了
We have for quite some time.
那  那你为什么还来这里
Then... then why are you here?
因为我需要你最后一次的帮助
Because I need your help. One last time.
爱丽丝  我
Oh, Alice. I...
塞勒斯获得自由
Cyrus is free.
我们就要重聚了
And we're going to be reunited.
在我们重聚时  我要你在我身边
And when we are, I need you to be there.
这样我们就回家  永远离开这里
So we can go home, and leave this behind for good.
对不起  但是我做不到
I'm sorry, but... I... I can't.
你能做到  而且肯定会
You can. And you bloody well will.
在你做了这么多事之后  你欠她太多
After everything you've done, you owe her that much.
我欠她的更多
I owe her more,
但是在是否该做和是否能做之间
but there's a difference between what I should do
还是有区别的
and what I'm able to do.
王后抓了我的家人
The queen... she has my family--
我的妻子和孩子
my wife, my children.
我所做的一切  只是为了保住他们的性命
Everything I've done, I've done to keep them alive.
很抱歉让你因此而受伤害
I-I'm sorry you've had to suffer because of it,
但你比谁都更清楚
but-- but you know better than anyone
当你爱的人身陷危险中
when someone you love is in danger,
你会不惜一切地去救他们
you'll do anything to save them.
我很理解
I do understand.
我也是
Me, too.
显然我也理解
I also apparently understand.
没人会知道你帮过我们的  兔子
No one has to know that you helped us, Rabbit.
红心王后会知道
The red queen would know!
就算你找到另一条离开仙境的路
And even if you found another way out of Wonderland,
她还是会怪我
she'd blame me!
我的任务就是留在你身边  向她通风报信
It was my job to stay with you, to be her ears,
告诉她你一切的行动
to tell her everything you were doing.
那如果我们把他们救出来呢
What if... we rescued them?
你的家人
Your family.
我们就能一起离开了
We can all leave together.
那你得先找到他们
Well, you'd have to find them first.
我已经找过每一个我认为王后
I've already searched every place I can think of
有可能关押他们的地方了
where the queen would hide them,
最后都没能找到
and failed miserably.
好吧
All right.
也许我能帮上忙
Maybe I can help.
我也许不知道王后贮藏重要物品的地方
I might not know where the queen stashed something important,
但我确实知道安娜斯塔西娅的贮藏地
but I do know where Anastasia might.
安娜斯塔西娅是谁
Well, who's Anastasia?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
我们来这干什么
What are we doing here?
是的  没错  精灵
Yes, that's right, genie.
你要做一个非常重大的决定
You have a very big decision to make.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
她不会有事的
She's going to be fine.
谢谢的
Thank you.
暂时的
For now.
暂时是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思说我们来帮忙
It means it's a damn good thing
是件非常好的事
that we were here to help.
但如果我们回不了家呢
But what if we hadn't been home?
下一次要怎么做
What about next time?
下一次我就会更加小心
Next time I'll be more careful.
那再下一次呢
And the time after that?
这对爱丽丝来说算是什么生活啊
What kind of life is this for Alice?
永远被追捕  睡在树底下
Always hunted, sleeping under trees.
这是我们一起选择的生活
It's a life we chose. Together.
你的选择不代表那就适合你
Just because you chose it doesn't make it right
或者适合她
for you or her.
爱丽丝还是个小女孩时  我就认识她了
I've known Alice since she was a little girl.
她一直想要个家
She always wanted a place to call home.
现在我们俩组成了一个家
I'm her home now. As she is mine.
你总是要用比喻说话吗
Yeah, uh... must you always speak in metaphor?
这是事实  我们也许没有温暖的壁炉
It's the truth. You know, we may not have a warm hearth
或一瓦遮头  但我们的命运联系在一起
or a roof to sleep under, but our life together,
这超越了我们的想象
it's better than we could have imagined.
正如我所说  这只是暂时的
As I said, for now.
但我们俩都知道  这不可能永远继续下去
but we both know this can't go on forever.
我在瓶子里待了很长时间
You know, I spent years alone in that bottle.
而你现在告诉我应该再次形影单只吗
Now you're telling me I should be alone once more?
如果我的家人陷入危险
If my family were in danger,
我会不惜一切地去保护他们
I would do whatever it took to protect them.
也许唯一真正能保护爱丽丝的方法
Perhaps the only way to truly protect Alice
就是让她走
is to let her go.
女王陛下
Your majesty!
人都去哪了
Where is everyone?
贾法尔亲启
我想她看穿我们的意图了
I think she's on to us.
贾法尔在你的棋盘那边  女王陛下
Jafar's on your side of the board, your majesty.
看来你的招数用尽了
It looks like you're running out of moves.
他可能摧毁了几个棋子
He may have destroyed a few pieces,
但是在象棋中只有一个王后
but in the game of chess there's only one queen,
就算其他的棋子加在一起  都不如王后重要
and she's more important than them all put together.
也许吧  但貌似现在下棋的不是贾法尔
Perhaps, but it doesn't look like Jafar's playing games.
也不是我
Neither am I.
告诉我  爱丽丝在哪里
Now tell me, where is Alice?
我为什么要告诉你
Why would I ever tell you that?
因为她就要被人找到了
Because she's going to be found.
问题是  是要被他找到
The only question is, whether it's by him...
还是我们
or us.
决定权在于你
The choice is yours.
我们打烊了了  派对结束了
We're closed. Party's over.
我不是为此而来的
I'm not here for that.
我来是要寻求你的帮助
I'm here for your help.
我做过很多事
Hmm. I've been called many things.
乐于助人不是其中之一
Helpful isn't one of them.
我听说你能让人消失
I've heard you can make people disappear.
只要他本人不想再被人找到
people who never want to be found again.
也许可以  但是这件事的代价
Perhaps. But the cost of such a thing
可不算小
is significant.
我只有一件珍贵之物
I own but one thing of any value,
如果你帮我  它就属于你了
but you help me, and it shall be yours.
这叫做失物指南
It's called a Lost and Found.
它会指向你丢失在人生中
It'll point you to anything you've lost in your life
又希望找回的东西
and you wish to find again.
你一定是想消失想疯了
Ohh... oh, you must really want to disappear
才会用这东西来换
to give up this.
这是唯一能保证一个人安全的方法
It's the only way I can keep someone safe.
一个我深爱的人
Someone I care about very much.
我也许可以帮助你
I may be able to help you.
-你和红心王后曾经住在这里吗  -不
- Uh, you and the red queen used to live here?! - No.
红心王后不会出现在这种地方
The queen wouldn't be caught dead in a place like this.
住在这里的是安娜斯塔西娅和我
But a girl named Anastasia and I...
我们曾在这度过一段快乐的时光
We had a few laughs here.
为什么你能认定
What makes you think this is where
她会把兔子的家人藏在这里
she'd be holding rabbit's family?
安娜和我会时不时得到一些宝贵的东西
Every now and then, Anna and I would acquire something of value
并且要想藏好那些东西
that we wanted to keep hidden.
我们的小木车是个绝佳的储藏地
Our wagon turned out to be a lovely hiding place.
瞧  这从外面看上去又破又烂
See, if it looks this shabby on the outside,
根本没有人会向里面看一眼
no one ever bothers checking the inside.
等着
Wait here.
你总是先走一步  不是吗
Always a step ahead, aren't you?
告诉过你了  这没用的
I'm telling you, it's no use.
爱丽丝  如果王后...
Alice, what if the queen...
如果我的家人已经...
what if my family is...
爸爸
Daddy!
亲爱的
Darling!
珀西
Percy?
-我的孩子们  -珀西
- My babies! - Percy!
亲爱的
Ohh, dears!
我的小兔子
Ohh! My bunnies!
My little bunnies!
我还以为我们再也见不到你了呢
I thought we'd never see you again.
爱丽丝  谢谢你为了让我们重新团聚
Alice... thank you for whatever you did
所做的事
to bring us back together.
不用客气
You're welcome.
好了  现在
Oh... okay, now...
记得我告诉过你们要信守承诺吗
Remember what I told you about always keeping your promises?
现在你们的父亲要开始履行自己的承诺了
Well, your father has to keep one of his now.
带他们到你母亲家去  我今晚去找你们
Take them to your mother's. I'll meet you there tonight.
小心些  亲爱的
Be careful, dear.
我难道不是一直很小心吗
Well, aren't I always?
你真想让我回答这个问题吗
Do you really want me to answer that?
好了  好了  我会小心的
Fine, fine. I'll be careful.
好了  孩子们  走了
All right, you two, come on, let's go!
好了  去哪
Okay. Where to?
去塞勒斯所在的地方  边境
Where Cyrus is going-- the outlands.
你凭什么可以认定她会去边境
Why are you so sure she'll be in the outlands?
因为她可以认定我会去那儿
Because she's sure that I'll be there.
你们俩还真是相当信任对方啊  不是吗
Ooh! You two have quite a lot of faith in each other, don't you?
如果连爱情都不能相信
Well, if you can't believe in love,
还能够信任什么呢
what can you believe in?
我信任什么与你无关
What I believe in is of no concern to you.
你心里有秘密  对吗
You have a secret, don't you?
别装作了解我
Don't pretend to know me.
我不需要了解你  当精灵当了这么久
I don't have to. Being a genie for so long,
我已经学会解读人心了
I've learned how to read people,
在人们开口之前我就能猜到他们想要什么
to know what they'll wish for even before they ask.
我想要你闭嘴
I wish for you to shut up.
你把愿望深深埋在心底  对吗
Your wishes are buried deep, aren't they?
别着急  精灵
Don't fret, genie.
你不用再担心这些了
You won't have to worry much longer.
你很快就会知道了
You're about to find out.
现在  告诉我我们还要赶多久的路
Now tell me how much farther until we're there.
快了  很快了
Soon. Very soon.
找到红心王后
Find the red queen...
然后杀了她
and kill her.
我听说过关于这座山顶的事
So I've heard stories of this mountaintop
在这里你可以真的站在云端
where you can actually stand on top of the clouds.
听上去不错
Yeah, sounds nice.
我想我们应该试试
I think we should try it.
就在我的伤好点之后
When I'm better.
塞勒斯
Cyrus?
怎么了
What's wrong?
爱丽丝  你还在恢复之中
Alice, you're still healing.
而事实是  无论我们走到哪里
And the fact is, wherever we go,
无论我们经历了怎样的冒险
whatever adventure we pursue,
跟我在一起  你是永远不会安全的
you'll never be safe with me.
塞勒斯  你已经把可能的危险告诉过我了
Cyrus, you've told me all these dangers,
我还是选择了你
and I still choose you.
但是  瞧瞧都发生了些什么
But look what happened.
也许我们陷阱了自己的幻想之中
Maybe we were lost in a fantasy.
我以为我可以保护你  但事实明显不是这样
I thought I could protect you, but clearly I can't.
塞勒斯
Cyrus--
我愿意不惜一切代价来保护你
I would do anything to protect you.
自己忍受痛苦也在所不惜
Even if I suffered for it.
你是想逃离我吗
Are you trying to run away from me?
如果这是唯一保证你安全的方法  我会的
I will if that's the only way I can keep you safe.
你有没有想过
Did you ever think
也许我才是保护你安全的人
that maybe I'm the one keeping you safe?
你的确很能战斗
You are pretty handy in a fight.
我不害怕这种生活  塞勒斯
I'm not afraid of this life, Cyrus.
唯一能伤害我的事
The only thing that could hurt me
是与你的分离
is being apart from you.
我想到了你会这样说
I thought you might say that.
所以我为你准备了些东西  为我们俩
Which is why I've got something for you. For us.
什么东西
What is it?
看这里
Look right there,
那块大石头的旁边
Next to that big rock.
我什么也没看到
I don't see anything.
正是如此
Exactly.
跟我来
Follow me.
这是什么
What is this?
这是我们能消失的地方
Somewhere where we can disappear.
外面看不到这里
It's invisible from the outside,
而里面相当舒适
but on the inside, it's quite cozy.
这不是个理想的解决方式
It's not a perfect solution,
但起码是个开始
but it's a start.
这样我们就能随心所欲地冒险
Now we can go on any adventure we desire,
我们有这里  一个可以回来的地方
and we'll always have this, a place we can return to.
一个家
A home.
是啊
Yeah.
太好了
It's perfect.
你怎么得到这个地方的
How did you get such a place?
如果你可以用魔法把它创造出来
If your magic could create it,
为什么等到现在
why wait until now?
这不是我的魔法
It wasn't my magic.
塞勒斯  为了这个你放弃了什么
Cyrus, what did you give up for this?
我放弃的远没有我得到的多
What I gave up--it's nothing compared to what I gained.
有人说  牺牲是
You know, they say that sacrifice
衡量真爱的标准
is the measure of true love,
我会为你做任何牺牲
and I would sacrifice anything for you.
我也会
And I for you.
你觉得塞勒斯可能会来这见你
Is this where Cyrus is supposed to meet you?
是的
Yes.
塞勒斯
Cyrus?!
我不想扫了你的兴  爱丽丝
I don't want to burst your bubble, Alice,
但你所谓安全的地方可不那么安全
but your safe place isn't all that safe.
从几英里外就能看见你
You can be seen from miles.
也许  也许他藏起来了
Uh, maybe-- maybe he's hiding.
也许他在里面
Maybe he's just inside.
里面  什么里面
Inside? Inside what?
该死的
Bloody hell.
你来吗
You coming?
我最好待在外面
Uh, better I stay out here--
望望风  省得有人来找我们
Keep watch in case anyone comes looking for us.
别轻举妄动
Don't try anything funny.
我不想做兔子汤  你别逼我
I don't want to make rabbit stew, but I will.
我知道  当然不会  我们都不想这样
I know. Of course not. We wouldn't want that.
一直以来  我们都餐风露宿的
All this time, we've been using rocks for pillows,
我们本来可以睡这儿的
we could have been sleeping here.
我们一直都在四处奔波
We were on the move.
我是说  有个歇脚的地方
Wouldn't have been a bad place to rest me weary feet,
总是好的
is all I'm saying.
那是浴缸吗
Is that a bathtub?
没道理啊  他应该在这儿的
This doesn't make sense. He should be here.
-还有别的他可能去的地方吗  -没有了
- Anywhere else he might have gone? - No.
也许他留了纸条
Maybe he's left a note.
你以为我在找什么
What do you think I'm looking for?
这儿什么都没有
There's nothing here!
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
我没想什么
I'm not thinking anything.
你在想他已经被抓住了
You're thinking he's been captured.
我可没说
Never said that.
你在想他在试图逃跑时被杀了
You think he died trying to escape.
还是你在想他从一开始就没能逃掉
Or do you think he didn't really escape in the first place?
我觉得他不在这儿  爱丽丝
I think he's not here, Alice,
也就是说我们快没时间了
which means we're running out of time.
也没有选择
And options.
兔子在外面
Now the rabbit's outside.
如果我们要离开仙境
If we're gonna leave Wonderland--
没有塞勒斯我们不会离开
We're not leaving without Cyrus.
我们不走
We're not.
塞勒斯
Cyrus?
爱丽丝  抱歉
Alice, I'm sorry.
-塞勒斯  -爱丽丝
- Cyrus! - Alice?
塞勒斯
Cyrus!
爱丽丝
Alice!
我以为我再也见不到你了
I thought I'd never see you again.
哪怕在梦里  我也不敢想象我们重逢的这一刻
Even in my dreams, I was afraid to imagine this moment
害怕它永远不会成真
and feared that it would never come true.
但你在这儿  你在这儿
But it's here. You're here.
我在这儿  都结束了
I'm here. It's over.
我可不敢说结束了
Well, I wouldn't quite say over.
你好啊  爱丽丝
Hello, Alice.
她在这儿干什么
What the bloody hell is she doing here?
她是来帮我们的
She's here to help us.
她要帮我们
She's going to help us?
你在开玩笑吧
You've got to be joking.
可没时间开玩笑  亲爱的
No time for joking, darling.
你看到那场逼近的暴风雨了吗
You see that storm coming?
那是贾法尔  他来找我们了  我们所有人
That is Jafar, and he's coming for us. For all of us.
她说的是真的  爱丽丝
She's telling the truth, Alice.
他为什么要抓你  你是他的搭档
Why would he be after you? You're his partner.
我曾经是他的搭档  没错
Was his partner. Yes, it's true,
我们曾经合作过  但我和他可不一样
we used to work together, but I am not like him.
当他开始不按规则出牌
When it became clear that he was no longer playing by the rules of the game-
别相信她
Don't believe a word.
她很会说谎
She knows how to lie, this one.
等我们离开仙境以后
We can argue all we like
想怎么吵就怎么吵  但现在
when we get out of wonderland, but for now,
快挖  兔子
dig, bunny!
我不会跟她一起走
I'm not going anywhere with her.
我们别无选择
We may not have a choice.
如果威尔是对的呢
What if Will's right?
如果一切都是精心策划的阴谋
What if this is an elaborate ruse?
爱丽丝  你还想让我干什么
Alice, what more do you want me to do?
我都把精灵给你带回来了
I brought you your bloody genie!
也是你把他从我身边夺走的
You took him from me, too!
爱丽丝  你得相信我
Alice, you need to trust me.
我永远不会相信你
I will never trust you!
爱丽丝
Alice.
告诉我理由
Tell me why.
为什么你做了这一切
Why you did all of this--
为什么你和一个疯子结盟
Why you made an alliance with a madman,
我会走
and I'll go.
但我需要一个理由
But I need a reason.
给我个理由
I need something.
我认为他能给我我想要的
I thought he could get me what I want.
-什么东西  -你已经拥有了一切
- And what was that? - You've got everything.
你还想要什么
What more could you need?
你  威尔
You... Will.
我想要你
I wanted you.
我想要你回来
I want you back.
又是谎话
More lies.
不  我现在说的都是实话  我说的是实话
No. I'm telling the truth now. I'm telling the truth.
你曾拥有过我  全心全意的我
You had me. All of me--
我的心  我的灵魂  我的一生
My heart, my soul... my life--
而你把我像垃圾一样丢在一边
And you tossed me aside like a piece of rubbish,
就为了那一顶红色王冠
all for a little red crown.
我犯了错  我现在意识到了
I made a mistake. I see that now.
难道你看不出我为什么这么做吗
Don't you see that's why I've done all this?
这样贾法尔就能改变这里的魔法法则
So Jafar can change the laws of magic
我们就能纠正错误  改变过去  威尔
so we can undo the mistake, change the past. Will!
威尔  等等
Will, wait.
我会放弃我的王冠  放弃一切
I would give up my crown. I would give up anything--
只为了回到你还爱着我的时候
everything just to go back to a time when you loved me.
求你了  威尔
Please, Will.
我想让你回心转意
I want you back.
永远不可能了
You'll never have me.
你在这儿
There you are...
亲爱的
Darling.
一会见
See you soon.
听着  你不用接受我的道歉
Listen, you don't have to accept my apologies,
但是你得接受我的警告
but you do have to accept my warning.
精灵在这里  瓶子在这里
The genie's here. The bottle's here.
愿望宝石在这里  你觉得贾法尔
The wish is here. What do you think Jafar's
来了之后会做什么呢
gonna do when he arrives, eh?
我们会走的  你来回应他
We'll go, and you'll have to answer to him.
不  因为你忘了一件事
No, 'cause you're forgetting something.
瓶子在我手里
I have the bottle.
我很乐意替你掌管
Which I'll gladly relieve you of.
爱丽丝  没时间斗了
Alice, there is no time to fight.
再斗就只有死路一条  我们得离开
There's only time to die. We need to leave.
我们得离开  拜托  我说的都是实话
We have to leave! Now please! I'm telling the truth!
我永远都不会相信你
I will never trust you.
我也不会
Neither will I.
我信
I do.
我知道你许了秘密的愿望
I knew you had a secret wish.
她说的是实话  爱丽丝
She's telling the truth, Alice.
所以拜托  我们带着瓶子快离开这里吧
So, please, let's take the bottle and get out of here!
兔子  挖洞吧
Rabbit, dig your hole!
-去哪  -只要不是这里
- Where to? - Anywhere but here.
小心
Look out!
我扶你  我扶你
I got you. I got you.
怎么了  他
What happened? Is he--
爱丽丝
Alice!
怎么回事  发生了什么
What is it? What's happening?
她许下的第一个愿望
The first wish she made.
她是保护威尔不受贾法尔的伤害
She was protecting Will from Jafar.
如果红桃杰克死了  我也会死
If the knave dies, then I die, too.
你没有八天了
You don't have eight days.
威尔
Will.
爱丽丝
Alice.
Alice?
你得听我说
I need you to listen to me, okay?
最后一个愿望  我们得用它来救你
That last wish--you need to use it to save yourself.
不  我不能让你回到瓶子里
No. I'm not gonna put you back in the bottle.
我不能再让你困在其中
I'm not gonna make you a prisoner again.
如果你能活着  我很乐意永远
I would gladly spend an eternity in that bottle
困在瓶子里
if you could live.
我爱你
I love you.
爱丽丝  不要
Alice, don't go.
爱丽丝  不许你这么对我
Alice, don't you do this to me.
我才刚找到你  我不能再失去你了
I've only just found you. I'm not gonna lose you again.
塞勒斯  我能救她
Cyrus! I can save her!
-怎么救  -因为那就是我的愿望
- How? -'cause that's my bloody wish!
他说什么呢
What's he talking about?
我不知道  是什么  威尔
I don't know. What, Will?
爱丽丝保证
Alice promised...
如果我帮她找到你
if I helped find you...
我就能得到一颗愿望宝石
I'd get a wish.
对我来说够了
That's good enough for me.
许愿要谨慎
Be very careful what you wish for, Will.
我希望
I wish...
结束爱丽丝的痛苦
to end Alice's suffering.
爱丽丝
Alice?
Alice.
塞勒斯
Cyrus.
你还活着
You're alive.
但是为什么呢
But how?
红桃杰克  他使用了他的愿望
The knave-- he used his wish.
但那就是第三个愿望了
But that was the third wish.
你为什么没有在瓶子里
Why aren't you in your bottle?
我的束缚  不见了
My binds--they're gone.
消失了
They're gone.
爱丽丝  我自由了
Alice, I'm free.
我不明白
I don't understand.
红桃杰克
The knave--
他许愿要结束你的痛苦
He wished to end your suffering.
你有部分痛苦
Part of your pain
是不能够和自己所爱的人在一起
Was not being able to be with the one you loved.
威尔  你真是个天才
Will, you're a genius.
他在哪
Where is he?
消失了
He's gone.
他本来在这里  现在消失了
He was here, and now he's gone.
什么意思
What do you mean?
红桃杰克怎么了
What happened to the Knave?
-不  -什
- Oh, no. - Wh--
什么  他在哪
Wh-what?! Where is he?!
瓶子在哪
Where's the bottle?
该死
Ah, bloody hell.